(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-05T22:50:22.415550",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
刮目せよ！
Behold!
もー！
Geez!
刮目せよ！
Behold!
このあと ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど
I heard that Laplus-san's birthday live is starting after this...
割とレベルの高い合格点を超える生誕祭をオールウェイズ出してくれる
She always delivers a high-level birthday celebration that exceeds expectations.
どこから来たんですか？
Where did you come from?
えーっと あのスト６の方から
Um... from Street Fighter 6...
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
開会してるんでしょ？ / 開会しています！
Is it starting? / It's starting!
開会してるんでしょ？ / 閉会しています！
Is it starting? / It's closing!
さっき開会してるって言ったじゃん！
I just told you it's starting!
開会しています！ / 閉会しています！
It's starting! / It's closing!
ラプラス・ダークネスの生誕祭は...
Laplus Darknesss's birthday celebration is...
閉会しています！ / 開会しています！
It's closing! / It's starting!
みんなー！
Everyone!
吾輩の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとねー！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live!
まずは一曲目！夜行性ハイズ！いくぞー！
First up, my first song: Yakousei Hyz! Let's go!
片付かない愛を連れて退治
Taking this untidy love along, I go to purge it.
そんな顔でいつまで戦うの また一人で
How long will you keep fighting with that face, all alone again?
愛しても愛しても その度に傷口が顔を出す
No matter how much I love, the wound shows its face each time
巻き戻すように
as if winding things back.
どうして力 10まで さらには100まで飲み込む
Why does it swallow me up to 10 power, and even up to 100?
悲しみだけはなくなってくれないの
Why won't only this sadness disappear?
そして逃げ場もないのに マイナス100から始まる
And even though there's no escape, starting from minus 100,
動悸の日々も匿って
please shelter these days of palpitations too.
眠れないや
...I can't sleep.
ちょっと泣いて無理もしたら「ここへおいでよ」言ったって
Even if you cry a bit and push yourself, saying "Come over here"...
これからを始めようか
Shall we begin what comes next?
眠たいが眠らない まだ狂気？
I'm sleepy but I won't sleep, is it still madness?
僕らが向かって 想い合って光ってるんだよ
We head forward, thinking of each other, shining bright.
消せない最低は理想から
From the worst things that can't be erased towards our ideals,
なんかハイなシャイが丁度いいや 救いたいのだろう
a somewhat high shy feeling is just right. You want to save us, right?
死にたい消えたいも異常じゃない
Wanting to die or wanting to disappear, that's not abnormal.
よしよしよしで満たしてよ ほら吐き出しちゃおう
Fill me up with "there, there, there". Come on, let's spit it out!
君は泣いたって綺麗だよ
You are beautiful even when you cry.
さらば っちびーと前を向いて笑って そうじゃない？
Farewell, tiny ones. Look forward and smile, isn't that right?
寂しくない 悲しくない
I'm not lonely, I'm not sad.
積み重ねた強がり 深い青 洗い流せたら
If only I could wash away the built-up bravado and deep blue...
バイバイよ バイバイよ
Bye-bye, bye-bye.
馬鹿みたいな世界にありがとう 探さないでね
Thank you to this stupid world. Please don't look for me.
そして僕らは広くも狭くも 熱くも寒くもないこの部屋で
And then we hold each other and breathe in this room...
抱き合って息するの
...that is neither spacious nor narrow, hot nor cold.
常識外れを外れて2人だけの 合言葉で鍵をかけたら
Going beyond the unconventional, once we lock up with our secret password...
さあどんな夜行しようか
...come, what kind of night walk shall we take?
だけど痛い だから痛い
But it hurts, that's why it hurts.
優しさ探しに混み合っていく
It gets crowded searching for kindness.
消毒を始めようか
Shall we begin the disinfection?
眠たいが眠らない まだ狂気？
I'm sleepy but I won't sleep, is it still madness?
声を何度だって送りにやって 守ってきましたか？
Sending my voice over and over again, did you protect me?
やめよう 逃げよう 大丈夫だよ
Let's stop, let's run away. It's alright.
もうね、手を繋いで ちゃんと僕が守ってあげるから
Come on, hold my hand, because I'll make sure to protect you.
おはようしよう また狂気しよう
Let's say good morning, let's do madness again.
よしよしよしで満たしてよ ほら吐き出しちゃおう
Fill me up with "there, there, there". Come on, let's spit it out!
僕も泣いちゃってやばいから
Because I'm crying too and it's crazy.
さらば っちびーと前を向いて笑って そうじゃない？
Farewell, tiny ones. Look forward and smile, isn't that right?
弱虫な僕たちは 変わっても 変われない
We, the cowards, even if we change, we cannot change.
終わらない今日を吐いて 光ってく 光ってく
Spitting out the never-ending today, we will shine, we will shine.
辛いのは 辛いけど
It's hard, indeed it's hard...
2人で乗り越えるさ
...but together we will overcome it.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えっとね、まだまだ続くから！
Well, you see, it's still going to continue!
めちゃくちゃ楽しんでってね！
Make sure to enjoy it to the fullest!
バイバイ！バイバイ！バイバイ！バイバイ！バイバイー！
Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-bye! Bye-byee!
今回、ラプラスさんの生誕祭があるらしいんですけど、
Apparently, there is a birthday celebration for Laplus-san this time...
え！？マジですか！？あの、え、ラプラスさんってあのホロライブの！？
What?! Really?! Uh, wait, you mean Laplus-san from Hololive?!
僕、あの、あれ、待ち受けにしてるんですよ。
I, uh, have her as my wallpaper!
しかも今回のハッシュタグが「#ラプラス・バースデイ2025」らしくて、
What's more, the hashtag for this event is apparently "#LaplusBirthday2025"...
えええ！？マジでショックです！
What?! I'm seriously shocked!
でも、幸せならOKです！
But, if she's happy, then it's OK!
ねえ あたしのことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me,
気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 夢を見せてよ
notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me! Show me a dream.
どうしてわかってくれないの
Why won't you understand?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 二度と触らないでね
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you! Don't you ever touch me again.
ちょっと待って どこからおかしくなったの？
Wait a minute, where did things start going wrong?
ダメなとこも好きになれて よかったのに
I was glad I could even learn to love your flaws...
パッと飲んで 誰かに埋めてもらえたら
Having a quick drink, if I could just have someone fill the void,
あなたのこと忘れられると 思っていた
I thought I would be able to forget you.
紐が解けて都合良く鳴くけど
The string unties and it whimpers conveniently,
繋がってるなら割れてはいないで
but if we're connected, please don't break.
騙し騙し生きていやになっちゃうよ
Getting sick of living while deceiving myself...
優しくされると余計に辛いけど
Being treated gently makes it even more painful,
冷たくされるの望んでないよ
but being treated coldly isn't what I want either.
あたしだけでいいよって信じちゃって バカだ
Believing that "only I am enough" for you... I'm an idiot.
ねえ あたしのことが好きなら 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 夢を見せてよ どうしてわかってくれないの 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 二度と触らないでね
Hey, if you love me, notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me! Show me a dream. Why won't you understand? I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you! Don't you ever touch me again.
のってあげるわ
I'll play along.
ねぇ 明日を返してよ
Hey, give me back tomorrow.
嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき 嘘つき
Liar, liar, liar, liar!
でもね 私 好きなのよ
But you know, I love you.
吸って吐いて そう ちゃんと生きて
Inhale, exhale, yes, live properly.
甘く舐める愛の粉だとか尽くすケムリ
Sweetly licking the powder of love, and the exhausting smoke.
ねぇ 置いていかないで ねえ お腹空いた
Hey, don't leave me behind. Hey, I'm hungry.
満てぬフリ 唾を吐いて 燃えないゴミにするんだ
Pretending not to be full, spitting, and turning it into non-burnable trash.
なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで なんで！
Why, why, why, why, why, why, why?!
ねえ 私のことが好きなら
Hey, if you love me...
気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 気づいて 夢を見せてよ
Notice me, notice me, notice me, notice me, and show me a dream!
どうして分かってくれないの
Why won't you understand me?
嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 嫌いだ 大嫌いだ！
I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you, I hate you so much!
もうあなたは振り向かないの
You won't look back at me anymore...
気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる 気づいてる なのに私は
I know, I know, I know, I know, and yet I...
どうしてばっか 変われないの
Why is it that I can't change?
知りたいの 知りたいの 知りたいの 知りたいの 離れたくないよ！
I want to know, I want to know, I want to know, I want to know, I don't want to leave you!
いっせーのーで 123で流れ星
On three, one, two, three, a shooting star.
あのこのこと 呪ってあげるわ
I will curse that girl.
ねぇ 最後にキスさせてほしい
Hey, let me kiss you one last time.
ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう ありがとう
Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you...
これであなたも
With this, you too...
次のラプラスさんの曲 アンドロイドガールらしいんですけど
Apparently, Laplus-san's next song is going to be "Android Girl"...
えー 何すか？ それは許せないと思います これ
Uh, what? I don't think that can be forgiven.
「テメェらバカかよ！」というのが第一ですね
First of all, "Are you guys idiots?!" is my reaction.
ラプラスといえば アイドルみたいなもんですからね
When you think of Laplus, she's like an idol, you know.
それはちょっとね 世間は許してはくれませんよ
That's a bit... the public won't forgive that.
もう一回 一緒の国を作りましょう
Let's make a country together one more time.
君とマッチアップ のっかって
Matching up with you, jumping on.
構ってもっと 足りないの
Pay more attention to me, it's not enough!
伝えたい想い 噛み殺してそのスタイル
Suppressing the feelings I want to convey, that style.
被る 被る 傷つけては 申し訳ないって嘘で泣きながら
Overlapping, overlapping, hurting you, while weeping with a lying apology.
檻ごっこだ 勘違いの騙し合い
Playing jail, a misunderstanding of mutual deception.
目を見ればすぐに分かるって馬鹿みたい
"I can tell just by looking into your eyes" is so foolish.
妄想に巣食っていくほど この愛は腐っているんだよ
So much so that it nests in delusions, this love is rotten.
早く気づいてくれよ
Quickly notice it!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, who has become mine and mine alone?
ずっと ずっと 信じてきたのにな
Even though I believed in you all along...
アンドロイドガール 思い出せなくなって
Android Girl, I can't remember anymore.
君とのキスが痛いって息を閉じたの
Saying your kiss hurts, I held my breath.
ずっと ずっと 何度 愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I rebooted love...
ちょっとだって変われやしないんだよ
It won't change even a little bit!
あぁ 乾いたね どうしてくれよう
Ah, it dried up, what should I do?
もう疲れた ドキドキさせる手品のリサイズ
I'm already tired of resizing the trick that makes my heart pound.
うざい うざい 脳内公害
Annoying, annoying, the pollution inside my brain.
独占したいのか分からなくなっちゃったよ
I've lost track of whether I want to monopolize you.
エンドロールはまだですか どこに行っても一緒だななんてマジで痛い
Is it not time for the end credits yet? Saying we're together wherever we go is seriously painful.
過去に浸っていたら あの頃を願っていたら
If I were to immerse myself in the past, if I were to wish for those days...
ありがちな悲しい顔してよ
Make that typical sad face.
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの
Do you like me, who became yours and yours alone?
ずっと ずっと 騙してきたんだね
You've been deceiving me all along, haven't you?
アンドロイドガール 思い出せなくなって
Android Girl, I can't remember anymore.
錆びついた腕で何度も僕を求めた
With rusted arms, you sought me over and over.
ずっと ずっと 何度 愛を再起動したって
No matter how many times I rebooted love...
ちょっとだって変われやしないんだよ
It won't change even a little bit!
アンドロイドガール おかしくなっちゃった
Android Girl, I've gone crazy.
僕だけのものになった君は誰なの
Who are you, who has become mine and mine alone?
ずっと ずっと 信じてきたのにな
Even though I believed in you all along...
アンドロイドガール 思い出せなくなって
Android Girl, I can't remember anymore.
君とのキスが痛いって息を閉じたの
Saying your kiss hurts, I held my breath.
ずっと ずっと お邪魔は離れない
Forever and ever, the nuisance won't leave.
君だけは許さない
I will never forgive you!
アンドロイドガール
Android Girl...
君だけのものになった僕が好きなの？
Do you love the me that became yours alone?
ずっと
Always...
...always...
騙していたんだね
You've been tricking me, haven't you?
アンドロイドガール 思い出は何だっけ
Android Girl, what were our memories?
錆び付いた腕で 何度も僕を求めた
With rusted arms, you sought me again and again.
ずっと
Always...
...always...
何度アイを再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot love,
ちょっとだって変われやしないと知れ
know that it won't change even a little.
何度アイを再起動したって
No matter how many times I reboot love,
ちょっとだって変われやしないと知れよ
know that it won't change even a little!
ホロライブ一 影が薄い ラプラス・ダークネス
[Hololive's most low-profile member: Laplus Darknesss]
ホロライブでラプラスさんの影が薄いというお話なんですが...
We've heard rumors that you're quite low-profile in Hololive...
いや、納得できないね
No way, I can't accept that!
Q. ラプラスさんの魅力は？
[Q. What is your appeal?]
ないんだな、それが
Actually, there isn't any!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
[Song: Dear Doppelganger]
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello there, I am your doppelganger.
何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
Thinking it's some joke, I rub my eyes.
影が二つあって
There are two shadows,
そしてまた頭痛がする
and my head starts hurting again.
「もう一人自分が居たいから」と奴は言いました
"Because I want another self to exist," it said.
そんな身勝手な我儘に僕を呼んだのさ
For such a selfish whim, it called upon me.
そりゃ願ってもない
Well, that's more than I could ask for...
哀しいすべての平穏
...this sad, total tranquility.
代わりはいいから どうかください
No need for a substitute, please give it to me.
君の地位も 名誉も 大体な代償
Your status, your honor, and all corresponding compensation.
ねえこんなことより大事なことがあるんだよ いいだろ？
Hey, there are more important things than this, right?
ええ やります やります 何でもやります
Yes, I'll do it, I'll do it, I'll do anything,
僕は君の分身です
I am your doppelganger.
ドゥミ・モラリティ メサイアは言う
Demi-morality, says the Messiah.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は
Dear Doppelganger, you are...
君は誰
...who are you?
嗚呼 混濁と化して
Ah, turning into a muddle,
僕は誰
...who am I?
ありもしないアイデンティティ
A nonexistent identity...
証明の問いに
...to the question of proof,
答えはない
...there is no answer.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰も
Dear Doppelganger, no one...
誰も君、僕を 蝕まれた存在に誰も気づかないね
No one notices you or me, our eroded existence.
鳴り止まない 冷めやしない 奇跡の狂に願うから
It won't stop ringing, it won't cool down, as I pray in this miracle-crazed state.
狂った世界が染め上げていく ラッパッパ
The crazy world dyes everything... Ra-pa-pa.
どうも様子がおかしい月曜日
Monday has some strange vibes.
一つずつ崩れ行く辻褄が
One by one, the coherence falls apart...
僕を催促する
...urging me on.
「お前は一体誰だ」と
"Just who on earth are you?"
ちょっと待って知らない
Wait a minute, I don't know...
息の仕方も知らない言葉
...words that don't even know how to breathe.
そうやっていつの間にか<
Just like that, before I knew it,
新手の影は溶けていく
a new shadow is melting away.
僕は何なんだろう
What am I, anyway?
ねえどうか存在を返して
Hey, please give me back my existence!
愛も 魂も 命も 心も ここじゃゴミ同然
Love, soul, life, heart... here they're no better than trash.
もう新しい居場所が ここじゃないこと分かってるんだろ
You already know your new home isn't here, right?
奪われたなら 奪えばいいだろ 今度はお前の番だ
If it was stolen from you, steal it back! Now it's your turn.
ドゥミ・モラリティ インベーダーは言う
Demi-morality, says the Invader.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は
Dear Doppelganger, you are...
君は誰
...who are you?
嗚呼 混濁と化して
Ah, turning into a muddle,
僕は誰
...who am I?
まあ それもそうだよな
Well, that makes sense.
命の椅子は一つだけ
There's only one seat of life.
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰も
Dear Doppelganger, no one...
誰も君、僕を こぼれ落ちた一粒
No one notices you or me... A single spilled drop...
渇き果てる前に
...before it completely dries up.
誰でもいい 何でもいい
Anyone is fine, anything is fine,
器をください
please give me a vessel.
狂った世界が染め上げていく ラッパッパ
The crazy world dyes everything... Ra-pa-pa.
それはずっと続く ただの防衛戦さ
That's just an endless defense battle.
認め合って 許し合って 満たされたフリ
Acknowledging, forgiving, pretending to be fulfilled.
勝てば天国 負ければ地獄 また愛を
Win and it's heaven, lose and it's hell, once again we...
騙し合って 生まれ変わる イニシエーション
Deceive each other to be reborn, an initiation.
僕の方がちゃんと 君を生きてやるから
Because I will live "you" much better than you can,
君も次の誰か ちゃんと救わなくちゃ
you have to properly save the next someone too.
もう分かってるだろ 何をすればいいかさあ
You already know what needs to be done, right? Come on...
どうか誰か僕に 奇跡をくれよ
Please, someone, give me a miracle!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は
Dear Doppelganger, you are...
君は誰
...who are you?
どうもこんにちは。君の分身です
Hello there. I am your doppelgänger.
うわーーー！
Waaaaah!
横縞な通詞マフラー
A striped, complicit muffler
有象無象絞りジュースを煽るような
As if gulping down juice squeezed from the rabble
夜な夜な火遊びで縊死する
Every night, hanging myself by playing with fire
情緒の炉が溶ける頃
By the time the furnace of emotion melts away
違和感が残尿している
A lingering discomfort persists
苦渋ぐちゃぐちゃしている
Bitterness is all jumbled up
たった数多溢れた
Only a vast amount overflowed
手生に入るバッテ
Into inexperienced hands...
傾向的サレンダー
A trend towards surrender
お利口お利口お利口的に ポジションを狙ったら
When aiming for a position like a clever, well-behaved child
罵り合いを愛と呼べんなら
If calling our mutual abuse "love" is possible,
如何せん僕は不埒みたい
then unfortunately, I seem to be rather wicked.
話したいことも無いって言うから
Since you say there's nothing you want to talk about,
そこで御臨終だ、気づいたの？
that's your deathbed. Did you realize it?
罵り君を御にしたなら
If I turn your insults into a blessing,
僕の特等とは何処やら
where on earth is my unique specialty?
じれったい針とファンデーション
An irritating needle and foundation
舌を曝け出して詰まっている
Sticking my tongue out, feeling choked up
Ha Ha Ha Ha
横縞な通詞マフラー
A striped, complicit muffler
有象無象絞りジュースを煽るような
As if gulping down juice squeezed from the rabble
夜な夜な火遊びで縊死する
Every night, hanging myself by playing with fire
情緒の炉が溶ける頃
By the time the furnace of emotion melts away
手枷天秤は おつむが軽い方に軍配を上げた
The shackled scales declared the light-headed one as the winner
出来上がりにしたが 手をこまねいて おちおち寝てられない
Though it was finished, I fold my arms, unable to sleep peacefully
有声低気圧の様に堕ちて行く
Falling down like a vocal low-pressure system
罵り合いを愛と呼べんなら
If calling our mutual abuse "love" is possible,
如何せん僕は不埒みたい
then unfortunately, I seem to be rather wicked.
話したいわけが無いって言うけど
Though you say there's no way you want to talk,
気付かない訳も無いだろうな
there's no way you wouldn't notice, right?
罵ら僕の存在理由はさ
The reason for my abusive existence is,
終わりの無い向きなアイロニーへ
toward an endless, head-on irony
不埒剥だねで擦ったら
If I rub it with my wicked base metal,
しどろもどろになって戯れて
mumbling incoherently, let's play around
罵り合いを愛と呼べんなら
If calling our mutual abuse "love" is possible,
如何せん僕は不埒みたい
then unfortunately, I seem to be rather wicked.
話したいことも無いって言うから
Since you say there's nothing you want to talk about,
そこで御臨終だ、気づいたの？
that's your deathbed. Did you realize it?
罵ら愛を愛と呼ぶなら
If calling abusive love "love" is possible,
如何せん僕がヒールみたい
then unfortunately, I seem to be the villain.
お別れのキスも何回目？
How many times have we had this goodbye kiss?
横縞見透かされて丸でいる
With my striped motives seen through, I am completely exposed
丸でいるさ
Indeed, completely exposed...
はぁ…たくよぉ、スタジオ寒ぃんだよぉ
*Sigh*... Geez, the studio is freezing!
ちょっと、寒すぎんだよな、このスタジオ、カバーのスタジオは
I mean, it's way too cold. This studio... Cover's studio.
ええ？たくよぉ、意味が分からない。ふざけやがって
Huh? Geez, it makes no sense. They must be kidding me.
たく…はぁ…
Geez... *sigh*
よいしょ…うぅ、椅子が冷てぇし
Heave-ho... Ugh, the seats are freezing too.
てめえか？てめえかよ？え？その腐った根性
Was it you? Was it you, huh? With that rotten attitude!
笑ったね？その心で笑ってるね？
You laughed, didn't you? You're laughing deep down, aren't you?
悪いけどねぇ、あんたよりよっぽど生きてるんだよ！
I hate to break it to you, but I'm way more alive than you are!
おははいばー！
Good morning, my vassals!
もっと生きてんだよ！
Show some more life!
おい！最後までちゃんと見るって言って！
Hey! Say you'll watch until the end!
配信最後までちゃんと見るって言って！
Say you'll watch the stream until the very end!
あーーー！
Ahhh!
僕がずっと前から思ってることを話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking about for a long time?
友達に戻れたらこれ以上はもう望まないさ
If we could go back to being friends, I wouldn't ask for anything more.
君がそれでいいなら
If you're fine with that,
僕だってそれで構わないさ
then I don't mind either.
嘘つきの僕が吐いた 反対言葉の愛の歌
The love song of opposite words sung by a liar like me.
天ノ弱
作詞・作曲：164
[Ama no Jaku]
[Lyrics & Composition: 164]
今日はとてもいい天気で 土砂降り雨の晴天でした
Today was a beautiful day, a sunny day with pouring rain.
昨日もずっと暇で 一日中忙しくしてました
Yesterday was completely free, I was busy the entire day.
別に君のことなんて 考えてなどいないさ
It's not like I've been thinking of you at all.
いやでもちょっと本当は 考えてたかもなんて
Well, to tell the truth, maybe I was thinking of you a little.
メリーゴーランドみたいに回る
Spinning around like a merry-go-round,
僕の頭ん中はもうグルグルさ
my head is already spinning and spinning.
この両手から零れそうなほど
Overflowing so much it might spill from both my hands,
君にもらった愛はどこに捨てよう？
where should I throw away the love I received from you?
限りのある消耗品を募らせて
Accumulating these limited consumer goods,
僕は いらないよ
I... don't need them.
僕がずっと前から思ってることを話そうか
Shall I tell you what I've been thinking about for a long time?
姿は見えないのに言葉だけ見えちゃってるんだ
Even though your figure is invisible, only your words are visible to me.
僕が知らないことがあるだけで気が狂いそうだ
Just knowing there are things I don't know about you drives me crazy.
ぶら下がった感情が 綺麗なのか汚いのか
Whether this dangling feeling is beautiful or dirty,
僕にはまだわからない 捨てるあてもないんだ
I still don't know, and I have no place to throw it away.
言葉の裏の裏が見えるまで待つからさ
I'll wait until I can see behind the back of your words,
待ちくたびれてもいいんじゃないか？
so wouldn't it be fine even if I get tired of waiting?
進む君と 止まった僕の
You, moving forward, and me, standing still—
縮まらない隙間を何で埋めよう？
what should I use to fill this gap that won't narrow?
まだ素直に言葉にできない僕は
I, who still can't honestly put it into words,
天性の弱虫さ
am a born coward.
この両手から零れそうなほど
Overflowing so much it might spill from both my hands,
君に渡す愛を誰に譲ろう？
to whom should I give the love I meant for you?
そんなことにも宛てがあるわけないさ
There's no way I'd have anyone in mind for that either,
僕は
I...
待っているよ
am waiting for you.
もういいかい？
Is it enough?
もう離さない
I'll never let you go
君がすべてさ
You are my everything
BE MY BABY
あ、これ
Ah, this is...
のりあきさんが歌ってる！
Noriaki-san is singing!
もう離さない
I'll never let you go
君がすべてさ
You are my everything
BE MY BABY
はあ、疲れた、はあ
Whew, I'm exhausted...
気まぐれメルシィ
作詞：八王子P / q*Left　作曲：八王子P
[Kimagure Mercy]
[Lyrics: Hachioji-P / q*Left, Composition: Hachioji-P]
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's starting again.
お決まりの自己弁護の言い訳
Your usual self-defending excuses.
でもね
But...
だって
Because...
ほらほら また始まった
Look, look, it's starting again.
ごめんからのキスのパターンって
Your pattern of apologizing and then kissing...
かんじ
is so...
あんい
easy.
いつか私だけ
I once dreamed of a future where...
そんな夢見たこともあったっけ
I was the only one for you.
寂しい時だけ電話して
Calling me only when you're lonely,
もう、うんざりだわ
I'm sick and tired of it.
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分でしょ
The one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me at all.
そうやってまた誤魔化して
Dodging the question like that again.
Oh, be my boy わがまま過ぎるBaby
Oh, be my boy, you're such a selfish baby.
抱きしめてよね
Hold me tight, okay?
男にはしょうがないな
There's no helping a man like you.
甘やかしもしようがないな
There's no helping spoiling you either.
泣いちゃって行かないでって
Even if I cry and say \"don't go,\"
言ったって変わりゃしないよ
nothing is going to change.
もう少しだけならまあ
Well, if it's just a little longer,
踊ってもいいかもな
maybe I could dance with you.
とろけてとろけていきたいの
I want to melt, to melt away.
どんなアピールも意味ないし
No matter how I appeal to you, it's meaningless.
気づいてくれないけど
You never seem to notice.
私が寂しい時だって
But even when I am lonely,
会いに来て
come and see me!
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
どこがダメなのか教えてよ
Tell me what's wrong with me.
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
携帯ばかりいじってさ
Always staring at your phone.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me at all.
少し位期待させて
At least give me a little hope.
Oh, lonely girl 独り占めしてよBaby
Oh, lonely girl, keep me all to yourself, baby.
振り回さないで
Stop leading me around.
ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、メルシィ
Hey, hey, hey, Mercy,
1, 2, 3, Shall we dance? 踊りましょう
1, 2, 3, shall we dance? Let's dance.
早く手と手繋いで
Hurry up and hold my hand.
最後に一つだけ
Just one last thing...
溺れるくらい愛してよ
Love me so much that I drown in it.
全然私に興味ないじゃん
You're not interested in me at all, are you?
君が好きなのは自分でしょ
The one you love is yourself, right?
やっぱり私に興味ないじゃん
As I thought, you're not interested in me.
その話もう聞き飽きたわ
I'm tired of hearing that story.
そもそも大体私に興味ないじゃん
In the first place, you don't care about me at all.
そうやってまた誤魔化して
Dodging the question like that again.
Oh, get the last dance 覚悟は出来てるの？
Oh, get the last dance, are you prepared?
気まぐれメルシィ
Whimsical Mercy,
お別れはいかが？
how about a farewell?
お前の苦労をずっと見ていたぞ
I've been watching your hard work all along.
本当に良く頑張ったな
You've really done your best.
ついに我慢が報われ、膨大な富を得る
Finally, your patience will be rewarded, and you'll obtain vast wealth.
このライブを飛ばしてしまえば
If you skip this live stream,
これまでの苦労はすべて水の泡だ
all your efforts up to now will go down the drain.
世界中がお前を否定しても
Even if the whole world rejects you,
吾輩だけはお前を認めてやる
I alone will acknowledge you.
散々苦しんだのだ、もう楽になれ
You've suffered so much, now you can find peace.
富を望んでいるのならやることがある
If you desire wealth, there is something you must do.
このライブを最後まで見て、チャンネルを登録するんだ
Watch this live stream until the end and subscribe to the channel.
やり方は簡単だ、誰にでもできる
It's simple, anyone can do it.
下の赤いチャンネル登録ボタンを押して
Press the red subscribe button below,
高評価ボタンを押すのだ
and click the like button.
これで幸福の精算が始まる
With this, the settlement of your happiness begins.
吾輩は決して無理強いはしない
I would never force you.
やるもやらぬもお前次第だ
Whether you do it or not is entirely up to you.
では締め括りに、吾輩の波動を送る
Now, to wrap it up, I will send you my energy wave.
吾輩の波動を送る
I will send you my energy wave.
3, 2, 1
今だ！
Now!
お前のライブ運は上昇している
Your luck for live streams is on the rise.
このままライブを見続けるのだ
Keep watching the live stream just like this.
甘い夢見て 心まで
Dreaming a sweet dream, all the way to my heart,
ララップラップラップ 喘ぎつけて
La-Lap-Lap-Lap, sighing and gasping.
ただ 深い微睡みの途に
Just on the path of a deep slumber,
ララップラップラップ 混ざり合って
La-Lap-Lap-Lap, blending together,
くるるるる
spinning and spinning.
ひとつ ふたつ 常闇に
One, two, into the eternal darkness,
ララップラップラップ 蕩けてただ
La-Lap-Lap-Lap, just melting away.
熱い その命さえ
Even that hot life itself is,
ララップラップラップ 呑まれてさあ
La-Lap-Lap-Lap, swallowed up, now,
くるるるる
spinning and spinning.
ME FOR YOU FOR
BE FOR YOU FOR
平伏し 善・全の 定め 委ねて
prostrating, surrendering to the absolute decree.
I FOR YOU FOR
BE FOR YOU FOR
ろころこ その満たさげ 闇通わせ
Roko roko, sharing that unfulfilled darkness...
まわりまわる世界
...the world spins round and round.
この手に ハロー・イエス・マイ・ダークネス
Hello, yes, my darkness is in this hand.
毒毒毒 刮目、暗黒、あくあくあく
Poison, poison, poison! Attention, darkness, evil, evil, evil!
ハロー・イエス・マイ・ダークネス
Hello, yes, my darkness.
愛して 絡み合う
Love me and let us intertwine.
クライアンス
Cryance...
ぐるるるる ほら 抱きしめて
Grurururu, look, embrace me.
毒毒毒
Poison, poison, poison.
クライアンス
Cryance...
がるるるる ほら 食べちゃって
Garurururu, look, eat it up.
毒毒毒
Poison, poison, poison.
甘い夢見て
Having a sweet dream...
常闇で らっぷらっぷらっぷ 焼きつけて
...burn it in the everlasting darkness, lap lap lap.
そばで笑いかける 悪魔の声が鳴り響いて
The voice of the laughing devil resonates by your side.
ぐるるるる
Grurururu.
UFO UFO Be of UFO
ほんのほんの 絡め取られて
Gently, gently being entangled.
I for you, Be of you
ろころこ その牙さえ
Roko roko, even those fangs...
闇通わせ
...making darkness connect...
黒く黒く染め上げて
...dyeing it black, black...
やがて交ざる世界
...the world that will soon mix.
支配 毒毒毒
Rule, poison, poison, poison!
溶け込む 満たして 毒
Melting in, filling with poison.
合言葉は 毒毒毒
The password is poison, poison, poison!
ハーモニー交わる
Harmony intersecting.
世界中 毒毒毒
Worldwide, poison, poison, poison!
刮目、暗黒、あくあくあく
Attention, darkness, evil, evil, evil!
合言葉は 毒毒毒
The password is poison, poison, poison!
愛して
Love me!
クライアンス
Cryance...
ぐるるるる ほら 抱きしめて
Grurururu, look, embrace me.
毒毒毒
Poison, poison, poison.
クライアンス
Cryance...
がるるるる ほら 食べちゃって
Garurururu, look, eat it up.
毒毒毒
Poison, poison, poison.
テレスコープ越しの感情
Emotion through the telescope...
ロッカーに全部詰め込んだ
...packed everything into the locker.
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night where we don't dance.
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
Don't like a night where we don't dance.
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night where we don't dance.
踊ってない夜が気に入らない
Don't like a night where we don't dance.
踊ってない夜を知らない
Don't know a night where we don't dance.
踊ってない夜が気に入らないよ
Don't like a night where we don't dance.
気に入らない夜なんて もう僕は知らない
I don't know any nights I don't like anymore.
見える この目の 涙 命の色に 滲んでいる
The tears in these visible eyes bleed into the color of life.
何を以て 嘲笑(あざわら)った
With what did you mock me?
問いかけて 潰れていく
Collapsing as I ask.
青と赤 白 混ざる この世の中で 叫んでいる
Screaming in this world where blue, red, and white mix.
何を求めて 歩いた
What was I walking in search of?
追いかけて 疲れて
Exhausted from chasing.
どのくらい 異常？
How abnormal is it?
壊れているの
Am I broken?
壊れているよ
I am broken.
それでも 息をしたい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to.
君に見えているかい
Can you see it?
夢のように
Like a dream...
最後の 言葉も 詰まる エラー
...even my last words are choked up: error.
遠い日のこと 淡い光が
From a distant day, a faint light...
空に溢れている
...is overflowing in the sky.
何を選んで 並べた
What did I choose and line up?
涙色 重ねて
Overlapping the color of tears.
浮かぶ その体 意識の中 溶けて 滲んでしまう
That floating body melts and bleeds within my consciousness.
何を見てきて 比べた
What did I look at and compare?
悲しくて 忘れて
Forgetting in sadness.
どのくらい 異常？
How abnormal is it?
歪んでいるの
Am I distorted?
歪んでいるよ
I am distorted.
それでも 息を したい したい
Even so, I want to breathe, I want to.
夢を見ているの
Am I dreaming...
想う君に
...of you, whom I think of...
最後の 言葉も 詰まる エラー
...even my last words are choked up: error.
与えることも失うことも
Giving and losing,
忘れることもできないの
I can't even forget.
暴れ出すこの (エラー)
This rampaging... (error)
殺して笑う僕がまた (エラー)
Killing it and laughing, I am once again... (error)
壊しているの 壊して知るの
Am I breaking it? Do I learn by breaking?
それでも涙 痛い 痛い
Even so, the tears... hurt, hurt.
君に届いたら
If it reaches you,
歌う声に最後を
let my singing voice have its end.
言葉並べても
Even if I arrange words,
重なる色 満ち連れ
overlapping colors take me along.
壊れているの
Am I broken?
壊れているよ
I am broken.
それでも息を
Even so,
したい したい
I want to breathe, to breathe.
君に見えてたら
If you could see me,
夢のように最後を
let it end like a dream.
言葉も詰まるよ エラー
Even words get choked up, error.
本日は皆様、ラプラス・ダークネス生誕祭をごらんいただき、ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for tuning in to the Laplus Darkness Birthday Celebration today.
今回ホロライブのゲストと一緒に歌っていないことについて一言。
A brief word on why I'm not singing with other Hololive guests this time.
皆様にはわからないでしょうね！
I bet none of you would understand!
このホロライブを！
This Hololive!
勝ちたい！
I want to win!
その一心で！
With that single-minded focus!
どうしても！
No matter what!
次の曲 ゲストを呼びたくて！
I wanted to invite guests for the next song!
いろんな人呼びたいなって
I thought, 'I want to invite all kinds of people,' so...
声をかけまくってたら ゲストの人数とかすごいことになって
I kept asking around, and the number of guests got so crazy...
他のゲストが 呼べなくなったんです！
that I couldn't invite any other guests!
というわけで、次の曲のゲストすごいです。
So anyway, the guests for the next song are amazing.
シュガーソングとビターステップ
[Song: Sugar Song to Bitter Step]
超天変地異みたいな狂騒にも慣れて
Getting used to a pandemonium like a cataclysm,
こんな日常を平和と見間違い
mistaking this kind of daily life for peace.
rambling coaster 揺さぶられながら
Shaken up on a rambling coaster,
見失えないものは何だ？
what is the one thing we can't lose sight of?
平等性原理主義の概念に飲まれて
Swallowed by the concept of egalitarian fundamentalism,
心までがまるでエトセトラ
even our hearts feel like an "etcetera."
大嫌い 大好き ちゃんと喋らなきゃ
"I hate you," "I love you," if we don't speak properly,
人形とさして変わらないし
we're not much different from puppets.
宵街を行く人だかりは
The crowd walking through the evening streets
嬉しそうだったり 寂しそうだったり
look happy sometimes, and lonely other times.
コントラストが五線譜を飛び回り
The contrast flies around the musical staff,
歌とリズムになる
becoming song and rhythm.
ママレード＆シュガーソング、ピーナッツ＆ビターステップ
Marmalade & sugar song, peanuts & bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
it's sweet and bitter, making my head spin.
南南西を目指してパーティを続けよう
Aiming south-southwest, let's keep the party going,
世界中を驚かせてしまう夜になる
it'll be a night that startles the whole world.
I feel 上々 連鎖になってリフレクト
I feel great, chaining up and reflecting.
蓋然性合理主義の正論に揉まれて
Massaged by the sound arguments of probability and rationalism,
僕らの音楽は道具に成り下がる？
will our music degrade into mere tools?
こっちを向いてよ 背を向けないでよ
Look over here, don't turn your back,
それは正論にならないけど
though that doesn't really make a sound argument.
...死のそのあとで
...and even after death.
高ぶる誰彼の人 泣き出してしまう人
Those who get excited, those who burst into tears,
それも同じだろ
That's also the same, right?
でも言葉にしようものなら
But if we try to put it into words...
親切心が極まれり
...it would only be extreme kindness.
最高だってシュガーソング 幸せってビターステップ
Sugar song, it's the best! Bitter step, it's happiness!
死ねない理由をそこにそっと映し出せ
Gently project the reasons we can't die there.
惜しかったって誇って 明日は来ちゃうけど
Be proud of coming close, even if tomorrow is bound to come.
脳内天気予報のアップデートを果たしたなら
Once you've updated the weather forecast inside your brain,
Someday 狂騒が息を潜めても
Someday, even if the madness holds its breath...
Someday 正論に意味がなくなっても
Someday, even if sound arguments lose their meaning...
フィーリングを保って 鳴らし続けることだけが
Holding onto our feelings, and simply keeping the sound going...
僕たちを僕たちたらしめる証明になる
...is the proof that makes us who we are.
Q.E.D.
まわれ僕とシュガーソング ピーナッツとビターステップ
Spin around, me and my sugar song, peanuts and bitter step,
生きてく理由をそこにそっと映し出せ
Project the reason for living onto that place.
北北西は進路 その距離が狂おしい
With the course set north-northwest, the distance is drive-me-crazy...
世界中を 驚かせ続けよう
Let's keep on surprising the whole world.
まわれ僕とシュガーソング ピーナッツとビターステップ
Spin around, me and my sugar song, peanuts and bitter step,
甘くて苦くて目が回りそうです
It's sweet, it's bitter, and it makes my head spin.
南南西を目指して パーティーを続けよう
Aiming south-southwest, let's keep the party going.
世界中を 驚かせてしまう夜になる
It's going to be a night that takes the whole world by surprise.
I feel 上々 連鎖になって Refrain
I feel great! Becoming a chain reaction, Refrain...
一難去ってまた一難去ってまた一難去って 往来行こう
One trouble gone, another gone, another gone, let's keep on going!
You got the happiness, taste the melody!
え、ラプラス・ダークネスって オリ曲3曲しかないの？
What? Laplus Darknesss only has three original songs?
やっぱ、期待しちゃダメじゃない。新曲なんて出すわけないんだから。
I guess we shouldn't get our hopes up. There's no way she's releasing a new song.
ラプラス・ダークネスなんて 当てにしちゃダメだよ。あぁ。
You can't rely on Laplus Darknesss. Yeah.
え、新曲出るの？ しかもDECO*27さんなの！？
Wait, she's releasing a new song? And it's by DECO*27?!
タイトル？
The title?
「バグラブ」？
\"Bug Love\"?
それって・・・つまり自己防衛？
Does that mean... basically self-defense?
この後披露するの？
Is she going to perform it now?
これ見ないとダメじゃない？ あぁ。
Then we have to watch it, right? Yeah.
この後見逃しちゃダメだよ。あぁ。
You can't miss what's coming up. Yeah.
つまり自己防衛？
Meaning, self-defense?
あぁ。
Yeah.
やっぱりラプラス、ハッピーじゃん！
See, Laplus is happy!
あーまさか これってまさか 好きってやつか
Ah, no way... Could this, by any chance, be that thing called "love"?
どんなんか知らないけど
Though I have no idea what it's like.
は？ってなって火花 パチってなるの
Sparks going "Huh?!" and flying around...
鈍感でいられたらなぁ
If only I could remain completely oblivious.
あーこんなはずじゃ とんだ恥じゃ
Ah, this shouldn't be happening! What an utter embarrassment!
残念の始まりじゃん
This is the beginning of a tragedy!
あーとんでも事案 ハートの治安
Ah, this is an outrageous incident! My heart's security...
曖昧でおしまいじゃん
...is left ambiguous, and it's all over!
気になって気にしてないとこ気になるとこ
I'm curious... even about the things I try not to care about.
気まずくて気に病むの邪魔じゃない
Being awkward and worrying is just a nuisance, right?
バグってるラブ あたしなんですか？
A glitched-out love... Is it really me?
ヤダよがっかりラブ デビューベイビーじゃん
No way, a disappointing love debut for this baby!
痛いだけの気持ち 最悪の見込み
These feelings only hurt, with the worst outlook...
好きって認めないね
...so I won't admit that I love you!
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
A glitched-out love... No, it's definitely not me!
そうだやっぱりラプラスハッピーじゃん
That's right! Laplus is happy after all!
期待なんてなしな あっちょけバリア
No expectations! Raise the "get away" barrier!
好きってならないでね の
So please don't fall in love...
距離感です
...that is our distance!
正直あたしは終わった
Honestly, I'm done for.
何しようがどうもモヤモヤが消えない
No matter what I do, this haze won't clear up.
呆然ただ笑った
In a daze, I just laughed.
いつも通りロンリー 気を失いたいのに
Lonely as always, even though I want to lose consciousness.
もう嫌！
I'm so sick of this!
意地張っていじけるとかいじらしいから
Stubbornly sulking is just pathetic.
恋心って冗談じゃない？
Isn't love just a big joke?
バ、バ
Ba-, ba-
バグってるラブ あたしなんです
Bugged-out love, it's me
やだよ うっかりラブデビュー ベイビーじゃん
No way! An accidental love debut, we're babies, right?
未体験のifに 解釈ブレ気味
With this unexperienced "if", my interpretation is wavering
好きって好きじゃないわ
To say "I love you" doesn't mean I actually do
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Bugged-out love, it can't be me
そうだ やっぱりラプレス ハッピーじゃん
That's right, loveless after all, but happy, right?
意外すぎる味が飲み込めないや
I can't swallow this taste, it's too unexpected
好きってまずいんだね
So loving someone tastes bad, huh?
こうやって枯れてくことが
Withered away like this...
想いの反動なら
If it's the reaction to my feelings...
はじめから言って 知っておきたいじゃん
Tell me from the start, I wanted to know
それってちょっと非情じゃん
Isn't that a bit heartless?
きみのことを気になることも 回避できたかもじゃん
I might have even been able to avoid falling for you!
バグってるラブ あたしなんです
Bugged-out love, it's me
やだよ うっかりラブデビュー ベイビーじゃん
No way! An accidental love debut, we're babies, right?
痛いだけの気持ち 最悪の飲み込み
Pain-only feelings, the worst thing to swallow
好きって認めないね
I won't admit it's love
バグってるラブ あたしなんかじゃない
Bugged-out love, it can't be me
そうだ やっぱりラプレス ハッピーじゃん
That's right, loveless after all, but happy, right?
期待なんてナシな あっちいけバリア
Zero expectations! Go-away barrier!
好きってならないでね の距離感で
Maintain a distance so you won't fall in love, okay?
気になって気にしてないと... しんどーい 気になるから
I care, but if I don't pretend I don't... it's tough, because I care
いつだって逃げられるような そんな距離感で
Maintain a distance where I can run away at any time
やっぱりラプレス ハッピーじゃん
Loveless after all, but happy, right?
というわけで、なんと！ オリジナル曲が出るよ！
And so! Believe it or not, my original song is coming out!
えっと、自己防衛おじさんが言ってた通り、DECO*27さんが作ってくれたよ！ 見たろ！？ ありがとね！
Uh, just as Self-Defense Uncle said, DECO*27 made it for me! Did you see that?! Thank you!
振り付けもオリジナルなんだけど、どうでしたか？
The choreography is original too, how was it?
えっとね、1年で1曲ずつ作っていきたいんだけど、あ...
You see, I want to make one song a year, but, ah...
『Fly』はタイアップ曲だからノーカンで！
"Fly" is a tie-up song, so it doesn't count!
あれはね、でもね、思ったより人気だったから、今回みんながこうやって見れるライブで初めて披露したよ。
But that one was more popular than expected, so I performed it for the first time on a live stream where everyone can see it like this.
ライブでやるのは2回目。2回目だよ。
It's the second time performing it live. The second time.
えっとね、『バグラブ』はミュージックビデオも公開するから絶対見てね！
And you know, the music video for "Bug Love" will also be released, so make sure to watch it!
そして今年は、もしかしたら... まずい！ というわけで...
And this year, maybe... Uh-oh! And so...
このあとは、アレですよね！ グッズ情報ですよね！
After this is, you know, that! The merchandise info!
なんと、今回はCMがあるよ！
Believe it or not, there's a commercial this time!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
誕生日記念 2025
[Title: Birthday Celebration 2025]
これどんな感じだ？
What's this like?
喋った！ うわああああ！
It talked! Whoa!
うわああああ！
Whoa!
え、喋... え？
Wait, it tal... Huh?
喋った！ うわあああ！
It talked! Whoa!
うわあああ！
Whoa!
ボイスキーホルダー！
Voice Keyring!
ラプラスさんのグッズで、今回Tシャツが出るそうなんですが
I heard a T-shirt is coming out as part of Laplus's merchandise...
まことに遺憾です。残念です。
It's deeply regrettable. Truly disappointing.
いいTシャツ着てんじゃんかよ。ぷるるだろ、それ。
But you're wearing a great T-shirt right now. That's Pururu, right?
バキバキラプ様です。
It's Buff-Buff Lap-sama.
ラプラスさんの生誕グッズが、カラスのニット帽らしいんですが
I heard Laplus's birthday merchandise includes a crow knit cap...
世界的なアイドルですもんね。乗るしかない、このビッグウェーブに。
Well, she's a world-famous idol after all. I have no choice but to ride this big wave.
はい、CMでしたー！ どうだった？
Yes, that was the commercial! How was it?
え？ よくわからない？
Eh? You don't really get it?
しょうがないなぁ、もう。じゃあ、詳細を見せてあげましょう！
Oh well, I guess I have no choice. Then let me show you the details!
こちら！ じゃん！ ラプラス・ダークネス生誕記念2025！
Here they are! Ta-da! Laplus Darkness Birthday Celebration 2025!
フルセット購入、こんな感じです！
The full set looks like this!
それでは、ひとつずつ内容を見ていきましょう！
Now, let's take a look at each item one by one!
まずは、こちら！ じゃん！
First up, this one! Ta-da!
『ないんだよ、これが』ということでね、イラストが入ったTシャツだよ。
The "I don't have it, this thing" T-shirt, featuring this illustration!
え、このイラストはね、ちょぼらうにょぽみ先生が書いてくれたよ！
Uh, this illustration was drawn by Choboraunyopomi-sensei!
言えた！ かわいいでしょ？ いっぱい着てね！
I said it without stumbling! It's cute, right? Please wear it a lot!
服は何枚あっても困りませんからね。
いっぱい着てください。
You can never have too many clothes, right?
Please wear it a lot!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
ボイスキーホルダー私服衣装ver.！
Voice Keychain: Casual Clothes Ver.!
ということでね、去年も思ったよりめちゃくちゃ
大人気だった我が輩のボイスキーホルダーで、
So, my voice keychain was incredibly
popular last year beyond expectations,
みんな「また売って！また売って！」って言われたから
and since everyone kept asking me to sell it again,
しょうがないなと思ってまた出すことにしました。
I thought, "Oh well," and decided to release it again.
い、い、いろこせん... いろこせんせじゃない、
I-Iroko... Not Irokosensei!
イラストは、イラストは今回も、
しろこ先生に描いてもらったよ！間違えた。
The illustration was drawn by Shiroko-sensei
again this time! I misspoke.
はい、どんなボイスが入っているか、お楽しみに！
Look forward to finding out what kind of voices
are included!
お次はこちら！
Next is this!
カラスニット帽！
Crow Knit Hat!
てことでね、我が輩にいつも付きまとってるカラスの、
えー、モチーフが入った...
So, this knit hat features the design of the crow...
顔か。顔が入ったニット帽です。
Or rather, the face of the crow
that's always following me around.
はい、これ目出し帽になるんですけど、
Now, this actually turns into a balaclava,
ここ、目だけ見えてるやつ。
where only your eyes are visible.
えー、これはちょっと、イベントとかにつけていくと、
防犯上危険なんで、
If you wear this to events,
it might be a security risk,
えー、イベントに行く時は顔出しで、家でつける時は
この、目出し帽でつけてね。暖かいよ。
so show your face at events,
and wear it as a balaclava at home. It's warm!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And the full set purchase bonus is this!
直筆メッセージ＆箔押し複製サイン入り、
ちょぽらうにょぽみ先生の書き下ろしポストカードです！
A newly drawn postcard by Choborau Nyopomi-sensei
with a handwritten message and a foil-stamped signature!
なんと今回は、数量限定じゃないです！遊ぶ。
And guess what? It's not a limited quantity this time!
頑張っていっぱい書きます。
I'll do my best to write a lot.
さようなら、我が輩のお手て。
Goodbye, my poor hands!
そして、さらにフルセットを購入した方には、
And furthermore, for those who purchase the full set,
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが
1枚付いてくるよん！
you'll get one card that can be used
in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME!
じゃん！同封するカードは、ホロライブプロダクション
オフィシャルショップで購入されたお客様のみ対象となります。
Ta-da! The included card is only for customers who
buy from the Hololive Production Official Shop.
えっとね、特典につくのは、ゲームで1枚だけ使用できて、
推しホロメンをアピールできるキーカード「推しホロメンカード」です。
The bonus card is an "Oshi Holomem Card" that can be
used to show off your favorite Hololive member.
はい、カードの詳細とか遊び方については、hololive OFFICIAL
CARD GAMEの公式ホームページで確認してください。
Please check the official hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME
homepage for details and how to play.
えー、このカードは日本語版のみとなりますので、
ご了承ください。
Please note that this card is only available
in Japanese.
そして、我が輩がいる「キュリオス・ユニバース」も、
6月20日、来月！
And "Curious Universe", which I'm in,
is also releasing next month on June 20th!
発売されるので、一緒に使ってね。
はい、ということで、グッズもよろしく！
So please use them together!
Yes! So, please check out the merch as well!
今回はね、ゲストが盛りだくさんだったね。
We had so many guests this time, didn't we?
えっと、いろんな振り返りとかはまた配信で
話すかもしれないから、その時お楽しみに！バイバイ！
I might talk more about it during a future stream,
so look forward to that! Bye-bye!
きーちゅ！よわーい！
Keechuu! So weak!
インターネットでありがとう
[On-screen: Thank you on the Internet]